Usman Ali

+358 466144280 usman_pervaiz@live.com

Summary

Full stack JS developer, REST, XML, Express & Node Js

Loaded with JS libraries & framework like Jquery, React, Vue and their state management libraries like Reflux, Redux, Vuex along with npm and node

Store in several databases like mysql, maria, postgreSQL, MongoDB, firebase

Fluent with major operating systems like Windows, Mac, Linux

Experienced with Mobile development in technologies like phonegap/cordova, react native, Android Java Play smoothly with HTML, CSS, SCSS, style frameworks, GSAP & several animation libraries Run business with Webpack, gulp, docker, microservices

Know the ERP science to operate systems like SAP, MS dynamics 365 & several accounts software Design with tools like Figma, photoshop, gimp, MS Word

Familiar with GraphQL, Docker, Microservices, Cloud(Basics)

Education

- a) Business and Information Technology, Haaga-Helia University of Applied Sciences, Helsinki 2016-2018
- b) Business and Information Technology, Lapland UAS, Tornio 2014-2015
- c) Master of Business Administration, IQRA University, Islamabad. 2009-2012
- d) Bachelor of Commerce, Alfalah College of Commerce, Gujrat 2007-2009

Experience

Craneworks Oy Ltd, Finland May 2018 - Present

Digital Signage Developer

HTML, CSS, SCSS, Javascript, Jquery, Gulp js, Webpack, Animations, React, Reflux, Redux, Vue, GSAP, XML, JSON, Electron JS, SQL, Rechart js, Node js, Express Js, Sql Lite

Responsibility: Templates & App development, Fixings & Maintenance

Haaga-Helia UAS, Finland Feb 2018 – Apr 2018

Android Developer: Location Tracking App

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sometry.usman.proretro

National Furnishers, Pakistan 02/2013 – 03/2014

Assistant Accounts - Daily Cash/Bank & Expense Report, Cash & Bank Management, Reporting to Directors, Inventory Management, communicating with banks & vendors, Approving work orders

ICT Skills

Operating Systems Linux, WIndows, Mac OS, Android, iOS

Front-end Html5, CSS, SCSS, BootStrap, Javascript, jQuery, ReactJS, React

hooks, Redux, Reflux, Vue js, JSP, Gulp, Webpack, NPM

Back-end NodeJS, ExpressJS, Java EE, Spring Boot, JDBC Mobile Technologies Android Java, PhoneGap/Cordova, Jquery Mobile

Query Languages MySql, GraphQL, MariaDB, MongoDB

ERP Softwares SAP SD, Microsoft Dynamics, QlikView, QuickBook Accounting Media Tools Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Gimp, Adobe After Effects(basics)

School Projects:

Salary DB: Users can login with their account made by admin and can see

their own salary. Admin can add, update, read and delete all

salaries.

Technologies: JavaEE, SpringMVC, JPA, H2 database, spring

security, Thymleaf for View.

NotesBoard: Users can add notes on a board and drag them as they want, each

note can be modified as edited, removed and moved

Technologies: React, ES6, CSS, ReactDraggable, NPM

TodoApp: Mobile App for planning daily tasks, including calendar, todoList,

weather forecast, calculating daily expenses. Technologies: Phonegap cordova, jQuery Mobile, jQuery UI,

Google api, ES6, BootStrap, LocalStorage

Camera&Restaurants: Mobile app where users can capture picture and see it by using

phone camera, geolocation will show nearest places as restaurants, fetch Amica haaga-helia's daily restaurant menu,

measure distance between 2 cities.

Technologies: Phonegap cordova, jQuery Mobile, Google API,

ES6, BootStrap, CameraPlugins

CarTracker: Description: Successfully launch android app where user can track

themselves and other users. Moreover, other's movements and maintaining the record of fuel recharged. Several persons can be

traced simultaneously.

Technologies: Android, Retrofit, Spring Boot, MySQL database,

REST, JSON, Maps Api,

Languages English Fluent in written and oral

Finnish Intermediate level in written and oral Urdu/Hindi Native in written(not in Hindi) and oral

Links

Linkedin profile https://www.linkedin.com/in/usman-ali-a46b7611b/

Github https://github.com/usmanali598
Portfolio https://usman-portfolio.netlify.com

REFERENCE

Available on request